Speaker: American and British English – the same, but different
American and British people speak the same language – English –
but with some small differences.
Vocabulary
Some words are different in British English,
for example, they say postcode not zip code,
holiday not vacation, and lift not elevator.
Some words have different meanings,
for example, in American English,
potato chips are thin slices of fried potatoes.
In British English, they are the same as French fries.
Spelling
Color, favor, and other words that end in -O-R in American English,
end in -O-U-R in British English.
Center, theater, and other words that end in -T-E-R in American English
end in -T-R-E in British English.
Grammar
There are some small differences, especially prepositions.
For example, British people say at the weekend,
but Americans say on the weekend.
Pronunciation
This is the really important difference between British and American English.
British accents and American accents are very different.
When British people start speaking,
Americans know they are British, and vice versa.